# **MARC BONTE**

### **Full Stack Developer**

+1 214 613 3968GA United State

@ marc.bonte.seniordev747@gmail.com

@ live:.cid.d63cfb795a360e89

# **SUMMARY**

Having a great sense Experienced with various kinds of software projects covering web,mobile, Al and Blockchain. Well -versed in numerous programming languages and great fan of masterpiece technologies (Django) and proper engineering practices (TDD & BDD, etc). Seek clarity in communication and being good team player. Proactive in making helpful suggestions out of rich battlefield experience.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend React Developer

#### **Journal Holder**

## 11/2016 - 06/2017 ♥ illinois

Medical Journal Holder

- · Developed 15+ websites of all sorts shops, blogs, forums, products, portfolios and advertisement
- · Had a deep understanding and utilizing on HTML, CSS, jQuery, XML, PHP and JSON
- · Created custom application for corporate departments, decreasing hours-spent by an average of 75%

### Frontend React Developer

#### Moneysource

Advertising Company

- · Built reusable components in modern frontend frameworks and libraries such as React.js, Angular, Vue.js and Next.js.
- Built user interface, data visualizations and designed overall user experience, resulting in 20% increase in sales

# Senior Backend Developer

#### BIZOO

**10/2017 - 06/2018** 

**♀** wuhan

**Animal Marketing** 

- Updated critical bugs with applications related to native code, device compatibility and version compatibility.
- Used JIRA for Agile project tracking and keep Sprints on track

# **Backend Developer**

#### **ONELOG**

**=** 02/2019 - 06/2020 **♀** ohio

E-gadget Manufacturing Company

- · Reduced technical production support workload by 25% by automating scripts for database backup.
- Established relations with up to 40 clients in all over the country.
- · Developed the user stories related to the backend which were implemented during each Sprint.
- · Enhanced performance by 15% and Dealt with vast amount of data in SQL, PostgreSQL, My SQL, MSSQL and MongoDB.

# Full Stack Developer

#### **Challenge Group**

IT company

- Integrate internally-developed micro-services, as well as marketplace 3rd party modules
- Managed 100+ client accounts and received 95% satisfaction with Django
- Worked in team of 4 college friends to develop a website last years during graduation

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor Degree of Computer Science

# **DeVry University**

11/2011 - 05/2016

LANGUAGES English

**Chinese** Advanced

**German**Beginner

**SKILLS** 

Native

Python React Flask Django Vue.js Angular SQL NoSQL AWS Clouds Github

Gitlab Pyramid Pandas ASP.NET

# **PROJECTS**

# Brantview Apples & Cider

**1** 02/2019 - 12/2019

URL: https://www.brantviewapples.ca

Language, Framework, Tool: Python, React, Styled-components, ¡Query

- Develop new user-facing features and refine and enhance existing features.
- Build reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.
- · Translate designs into high quality code.
- · Optimize components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers.
- Contribute in all phases of the development lifecycle.

# TGTA - Affaires Immobilieres

**1** 01/2018 - 05/2018

URL: https://www.tgta.ca

Language, Framework, Tool: python, Django, Bootstrap, jQuery, ubuntu, ngnix

- Write well-designed, efficient, and testable code.
- Execute all visual design stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering.
- Conceptualize original website design ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex roadblocks.

#### Clover Mortage

**11/2020 11/2020** 

URL: https://www.clovermortgage.ca

Language, Framework, Tool: Python, Django, ubuntu, ngnix

- Create wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps to communicate interaction and design ideas.
- Present and defend designs and key deliverables to peers and executive level stakeholders.
- Establish and promote design guidelines, best practices and standards.

# **CERTIFICATE**

# Certificate of Computer Service

San Diego College

**6** 06/2017 - 05/2019